Finding Aid for the Henry Miller Papers LSC.0110
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Manuscripts, 1896-1980; 33 boxes, 4.5 oversized boxes (18.5 linear ft.)
  - Literary manuscripts by Miller, 1896-1978; 22 boxes, 4.5 oversized boxes (13 linear ft.)
    - Letters to Emil Schnellock. Typescript (2 of 6), 1930; 6 items. (Box 158, Folder 5)
    - Letters to Emil Schnellock. Typescript (3 of 6), 1931; 18 items. (Box 158, Folder 6)
    - Letters to Emil Schnellock. Typescript (4 of 6), 1932; 22 items. (Box 158, Folder 7)
    - Letters to Emil Schnellock. Typescript (5 of 6), 1933; 32 items. (Box 158, Folder 8)
    - Letters to Emil Schnellock. Typescript (6 of 6), 1934-1939; 1 items. (Box 159, Folder 1)
      Selections from these letters were used as text in Miller's Semblance of a Devoted Past (Berkley: Bern Porter, 1944) and in Miller's The Waters Reglitterized (San Jose: John Kiddiss, 1950). See also Series I for correspondence with mil Schnellock.
    - Sexus, vols. 1-3, 1941-1949; 1 items. (Box 159, Folder 2)
    - Sexus, vols. 4-5, 1941-1949; 1 items. (Box 159, Folder 3)
    - "The sleeping sleeper asleep", undated; 1 items. (Box 159, Folder 4)
      Unpublished typescript with holograph corrections.
    - "Sommieres", undated.; 9 items. (Box 159, Folder 5)
      Unpublished typescript, 1 leaf.
    - Stand Still Like the Humming Bird. "Children of the earth", circa 1953-1958; 2 items. (Box 159, Folder 6)
      Assorted typescripts and one holograph draft. Includes two letters regarding the drafts, one from Karl Shapiro and the other from Carmody.
    - The Books in My Life. "Prospective chapters for book about books", undated; 2 items. (Box 160, Folder 1)
      Oversized holograph lists, 28 x 36 cm.
    - August 2nd: Neptune enters Libra for 14 years..., undated; 1 items. (Box 160, Folder 2)
      Oversized holograph manuscript, 1 leaf, 30 X 46 cm. Note reads: "For Jack Wright, souvenir of a tormented period." Painting on verso.
    - "Notice to Visitors", undated; 2 items. (Box 160, Folder 3)
      Oversized. 3 leaves, 32 x 50 cm. Also includes fragmentary notes and drawings.
    - "Grosz' 'A little yes and a big no!'" [Notes], undated; 1 items. (Box 160, Folder 4)
      Oversized holograph manuscript, 2 leaves, 30 x 50 cm.
    - Notes and watercolor strokes, undated; 1 items. (Box 160, Folder 5)
      Oversized. Holograph notes, 1 sheet, 40 x 40 cm. Miscellaneous notes regarding paint colors and some other writing. Written on the back of a leaf from a calendar depicting a drawing entitled "Two girls standing in water."
    - "Words", undated; 1 items. (Box 160, Folder 6)
      Holograph manuscript, 2 leaves, 37 x 51 cm. Lists of words with some underlining by Miller.
    - Plans for "The World of Lawrence", undated; 1 items. (Box 162, Folder 5)
      Oversized. 2 leaves, 25 x 30 cm.
    - Plans for "Tropic of Capricorn", undated; 1 items. (Box 162, Folder 6)
      Oversized. 1 leaf, 24 x 35. In pencil, ink, and crayon.
    - The Angel is My Watermark. Layouts, circa 1944; 1 items. (Box 164, Folder 1)
      Production matter for the Holve-Barrows edition of the book, 1944.
    - The Angel is My Watermark. Negatives and notes, circa 1944; 1 items. (Box 164, Folder 2)
    - The Angel is My Watermark. Print blocks, circa 1944; 4 items. (Box 164, Folder 3)
  - Prefaces and reviews by Miller, 1939-1964; 1 box (.5 linear ft.)
    This subseries consists of Miller's prefaces, reviews, and introductions to works by other authors. Manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by the surname of the author being reviewed. Prefaces to Miller's own works can be found in subseries 2A. Literary manuscripts by Miller.
    - Preface to Zande Allan's The Stranger in Big Sur, 1948; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 1)
      Typescript entitled "Preface to The Stranger."
    - Preface for Jack Kerouac's The Subterraneans, undated; 2 items. (Box 142, Folder 2)
      Typescripts. Preface for Avon Pocketbook edition.
    - Preface for Eric Wilson Barker's A Ring of Willows, 1958 January 29; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 2)
    - Preface for H. E. Bates' Seven by Five, circa 1963; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 3)
      Carbon typescript. Incomplete preface for the collected short stories. Note on final page of typescript reads "Rest added in ink - no copy. H. M."
    - Preface to Brassaï's Conversations Avec Picasso, undated; 2 items. (Box 142, Folder 4)
      Typescripts, one with holograph corrections.
    - "Review of [Beniamino] Bufano's album", 1957; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 5)
    - Preface for George Dibbern's Quest, 1963 June 6; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 6)
    - Introduction to the "new American edition" of The Black Book by Lawrence Durrell, 1945; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 7)
    - Preface to Lawrence Durrell's The Black Book, circa 1945, 1958; 5 items. (Box 142, Folder 8)
      Unpublished typescripts with holograph corrections, intended as a preface.
    - Review of Lawrence Durrell's The Black Book, entitled "A boost for The Black Book", undated; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 9)
    - Review of Lawrence Durrell's Justine, entitled "A few golden worlds about Lawrence Durrell's Justine as commanded by Herr Ledig of Rowohlt", 1957 May 15; 4 items. (Box 142, Folder 10)
      Typescripts.
    - Review of Lawrence Durrell's Justine, entitled "On Lawrence Durrell's Justine", 1957 July 19; 6 items. (Box 142, Folder 11)
    - Preface to Elie Faure's History of Art, circa 1939; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 12)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, 15 leaves. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - Review of Adreas Feininger's Women Throughout the Ages, 1960 March 15; 2 items. (Box 142, Folder 13)
      Typescripts with holograph corrections. Second typescript inscribed in blue ink, "Preface for book of 200 photos of women, all time. To be pub. by Dumont Schauberg, Cologne, February."
    - Review of Wallace Fowlie's Clowns and Angels, 1944 August 8; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 14)
      Inscription: "Published by Sheed and Ward, New York, 1943. For 'Chimera' magazine, New York."
    - Preface for Carlay Gannon's Poems, 1949 March 14; 2 items. (Box 142, Folder 15)
      Typescript with holograph corrections. Includes 19 poems by Carlay Gannon.
    - Preface to George Grosz' Ecce Homo, circa 1965; 3 items. (Box 142, Folder 16)
      Two typescript drafts. Also includes 7 pages holograph notes. See box 123 for oversized notes relating to this material.
    - Review of Eric Gutkind's The Absolute Collective. Typescript, 5 leaves, undated; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 17)
      From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - Review of Eric Gutkind's The Absolute Collective. Typescript with holograph notes, undated; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 18)
    - Preface for Claude Houghton's I am Jonathan Scrivne, 1953 April; 3 items. (Box 142, Folder 19)
      Holograph and carbon typescripts. Inscribed "Preface for French editions."
    - Review of Hugh Kingsmill's D.H. Lawrence, 1947 May 31; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 21)
    - Review for the Comte de Lautréamont's Maldoror, entitled "Let us be content with three little new born elephants", 1944; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 22)
      Typescript with holograph corrections. Review published in Accent, Autumn 1944, p. 48.
    - Review for Harold Maine's If a Man be Mad, entitled "Alcoholism: a religious phenomenon?", undated; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 23)
    - Preface to Dennis Murphy's The Sergeant, undated; 5 items. (Box 142, Folder 24)
      Typescript and holograph notes. Multiple drafts.
    - Preface and other materials related to Bob Nash's Journey to an Antique Land, 1958-1960; 6 items. (Box 142, Folder 25)
      Assorted typescripts drafts and 3 drawings by Bob Nash, 9 x 15 cm.
    - Review of Gilbert Neiman's There is a Tyrant in Every Country., 1947 May 31; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 26)
      Carbon typescripts. Inscribed in pencil: "Dallas 'News' (Texas) June 15, 1947."
    - Forward, postscript, and correspondence for Sydney Omarr's Henry Miller: His World of Urania, circa 1956; 9 items. (Box 142, Folder 27)
      Two typescript drafts entitled "Postscriptum" and two typescript drafts entitled "The Astrology of Henry Miller." Includes 5 letters between Miller and Omarr regarding the work. See also the "Preface" to this work, written by James Boyer May, in the manus[cript].
    - Preface to Sydney Omarr's Henry Miller: His World of Urania, 1956 July 26; 2 items. (Box 142, Folder 28)
      Carbon typescripts, entitled "Preface to The Astrology of Henry Miller by S. O." Second typescript dated 16 October 1956, and entitled "Continuation to forward to Astrology of H. M."
    - Preface to Sun of Death by Pandelis Prevelakis, 1964; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 29)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, 3 leaves. Printed in the English translation published by Simon and Schuster, 1964.
    - Review of Raymond Queneau's The Skin of Dreams, undated; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 30)
      Holograph notes.
    - Preface for an untitled, unpublished work by Abraham Rattner, 1956 September 10; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 31)
      Carbon typescript. Inscribed in ink: "For Rattner book to be pub. by New Directions."
    - "Review of [Kenneth] Rexroth", undated; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 32)
      Incomplete typescript with holograph corrections, 3 leaves.
    - Forward to Portfolio of Illustrations by Bezalel Schatz., 1957; 2 items. (Box 142, Folder 33)
      Two drafts, one with holograph corrections.
    - Review of Short Friday by Issac Bachevis Singer, entitled "Happy is the man who can renew himself together with creation.", circa 1964; 10 items. (Box 142, Folder 34)
      Assorted typescript drafts. Written for "Life." Also includes correspondence regarding the piece and several clippings of other reviews.
    - Review of the work of Saint John Perse, entitled "...A Saint-John Perse", circa 1957; 2 items. (Box 142, Folder 35)
      Two drafts, one with holograph corrections. Published in "Combat," (May 16, 1957).
    - Preface for "Chair et metal" by Eugene [last name unidentified], 1958 January 10; 2 items. (Box 143, Folder 1)
      Two typescripts, one with holograph corrections
    - "Varda", 1957; 3 items. (Box 143, Folder 2)
      Three typescript drafts, one with extensive holograph corrections.
    - Postscript for George Wickes' Henry Miller and the Critics, entitled "Draconian postscript", 1962; 2 items. (Box 143, Folder 3)
      Typescripts with holograph corrections.
    - Review of Bernard Wolfe's Really the Blues, 1948; 3 items. (Box 143, Folder 4)
      Carbon typescript with holograph corrections, includes two mimeograph copies.
  - Manuscripts by others, 1931-1980; 10 boxes (5 linear ft.)
    Arranged alphabetically by the surname of the author.
    - Durrell, Lawrence. Henry Miller Reader, circa 1959; 2 items. (Box 101, Folder 1)
      Introduction and table of contents. Includes a letter from Miller to Durrell regarding the preface.
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence. Coney island of the mind, undated; 1 item. (Box 101, Folder 2)
      Typescript. Inscribed by the author "Thanks for the title."
    - Fink, Robert. "What became of the snakes?: a profile of the last bohemian, Henry Miller", 1973; 1 item. (Box 101, Folder 3)
      Typescript (photocopy). Inscribed "preface to book on Miller."
    - Fraenkel, Michael. "25 notes on the present state of weather", 1932; 1 item. (Box 101, Folder 4)
      Typescript with holograph notes. From Emil Schnellock's papers.
    - Fraenkel, Michael. "The genesis of the Tropic of Cancer", 1944-1946; 16 items. (Box 101, Folder 5)
      Typescripts, proofs, and 11 letters from Fraenkel to Bern Porter pertaining mainly to the publication. Appears in The Happy Rock (Berkeley: Bern Porter, 1945). Also published as separate item by Bern Porter, Berkeley, 1946.
    - Gimpel, Peter. The Carnevalis of Eusebius Asch, 1968; 1 item. (Box 101, Folder 6)
      Typescript (photocopy). Inscribed to Miller.
    - Girodias, Maurice. "President Kissinger, or: the politics of politics", circa 1976; 1 item. (Box 101, Folder 7)
      Typescript (photocopy). Includes letter from Girodias.
    - Griffin, David W. "The possibility of joy: Henry Miller's place in the American tradition", undated; 2 items. (Box 101, Folder 8)
      Carbon copies.
    - [Hemal, Ginelle?] [Unidentifeid work]. "Conclusion", 1975; 1 item. (Box 101, Folder 9)
      Typescript. Includes letter to Miller.
    - Houghton, Claude. Assorted typescripts, undated; 2 items. (Box 101, Folder 10)
      Titles include "The man who dreamed the same dream" and "The thing that happened to me: a fantastic tale." Copied from The Aryan Path, January 1955.
    - Javan, Minoo. "A talk between H. M. and Minoo Javan", undated; 2 items. (Box 101, Folder 11)
      Typescripts and one holograph drafts. Minoo Javan was an Iranian folk singer and law student in Teheran, Iran at the time of her meeting with Miller.
    - Jones, Roger. "The air-conditioned evening: Henry Miller at eighty-five", undated; 1 item. (Box 101, Folder 12)
      Typescript (photocopy).
    - Kimble, Stephen Berry. "Henry Miller: The conditions and achievements of freedom...", 1965; 1 item. (Box 101, Folder 13)
      Typescript, 58 leaves. Thesis presented at the University of Idaho.
    - Lancaster, June. "Notes on H. M.", undated; 1 item. (Box 101, Folder 14)
      5 pages of holograph notes written by June Lancaster for Bern Porter giving her impressions of Miller during his time at Partington Ridge.
    - Lesdain, Pierre. "Quelque poëmes pour Henry Miller", 1952; 1 item. (Box 101, Folder 15)
      Illustrated by Francoise Lambilliotte and Maurice Wyckaert.
    - Lipton, Lawrence. "The ultimate weapon", undated; 2 items. (Box 102, Folder 1)
      Typescript of poem. Also includes a typescript copy of an interview of Lipton by William Kenneally.
    - Manning, Hugo. "Faith-love-fun chez Henry Miller", 1969; 1 item. (Box 102, Folder 2)
      Typescript. Includes a letter from Manning to Miller.
    - Manning, Hugo. "The faith-love-fun of Henry Miller", 1970; 1 item. (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Manning, Hugo. "The mediation of Aldous Huxley", 1969; 1 item. (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Martin, Jay. Always Merry and Bright, 1978; 1 item. (Box 102, Folder 5)
      Uncorrected galley proofs, 225 p. Published by Capra Press, Santa Barbara, c1978.
    - Mathieu, Bertrand. "Proposal for a dissertation", undated; 1 item. (Box 102, Folder 6)
      Typescript (photocopy). Proposal to the University of Arizona Department of English.
    - Mathieu, Bertrand. "A room in the house of art: the friendship of Anaïs Nin and Lawrence Durrell", undated; 1 item. (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - May, James Boyer. Preface to Henry Miller: His World of Urania, 1959; 1 item. (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts by various persons, circa 1946-1961; 25 items. (Box 102, Folder 9)
      Assorted typescripts.
    - Moricand, Conrad. "L'oeuvre et la genie de Balzac devant l'astrologie", undated; 1 item. (Box 102, Folder 10)
      Carbon typescript, 10 leaves. Copied by Henry Miller and sent to his friend Robert Osborn.
    - Moricand, Conrad. "Pages curieuses des grands occultistes, Tome I", undated; 1 item. (Box 102, Folder 11)
      Gift from Conrad Moricand to Henry Miller in 1938.
    - Moricand, Conrad. "Pages curieuses des grands occultistes, Tome II", undated; 1 item. (Box 102, Folder 12)
    - Morice-Kerné, A. "Happy reading", undated; 2 items. (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Omarr, Sydney. "Sydney Omarr's almanac", 1956; 1 item. (Box 103, Folder 2)
      Typescript. Inscribed by Omarr "Henry, I would appreciate any comment."
    - Osborn, R. G. "Epitaph of the late Henry V. Miller", undated; 1 item. (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - Patton, Bart. "The smile at the foot of the ladder", circa 1968; 1 item. (Box 103, Folder 4)
      Screenplay adaptation, 145 leaves.
    - Perlès, Alfred. "The holy leaf", circa 1954; 2 items. (Box 103, Folder 5)
      Two typescripts with corrections by the author and Miller. Note on title page: "A dissertation on the art and science of smoking." Unpublished.
    - Perlès, Alfred. "My friend Henry Miller", 1954-1955; 3 items. (Box 103, Folder 6)
      Two typescripts with corrections by Miller. Includes a holograph letter from Miller to Lawrence Clark Powell explaining Miller's corrections on ms.
    - Polly, George Warren. "Credo for a new age: Henry Miller and Nikos Kazantzakis as religious writers.", undated; 1 item. (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Perlès, Alfred. "My friend Henry Miller." Galleys (incomplete), undated; 1 item. (Box 103, Folder 7)
      Pages 71-74.
    - Perlès, Alfred. "Now blessed Venus", n. d.; 1 item. (Box 103, Folder 8)
      Unpublished typescript. Inscribed "A dissertation on love and women and how to keep them happy." Presented by the author to Miller.
    - Perlès, Alfred. "Why I Write", 1945; 1 item. (Box 103, Folder 9)
      Typescript. Inscribed "Specially written for Gangrel."
    - Bibalo, Antonio. "Sorriso ai piedi d'una scala: Opera in 2 atti e 5 quadri", circa 1964; 2 items. (Box 105, Folder 2)
      Oversized. Blueprint with music and libretto. Text in both Italian and German, with a few parts also in French. Vol. 2 contains manuscript corrections and additions. Gift of Robert Snyder.
    - Porter, Bern. The Happy Rock. [Contributors' original mss.], circa 1944-1945; 20 items. (1st folder) 21 items. (2nd folder) (Box 107, Folder 2, Folder 1)
      Assorted typescripts. Includes mss. both used in the collection and those rejected. Corrections by authors, Henry Miller, and Bern Porter.
    - Porter, Bern. The Happy Rock. [Contributions not in order of publication.], circa 1944-1945; 2 items. (Box 107, Folder 3)
      Assorted typescripts. Includes holograph notes taken by Porter on a discussion of water colors by Miller.
    - Porter, Bern. The Happy Rock. Correspondence from contributors, circa 1944-1945; ca. 53 items. (Box 107, Folder 4)
      Includes letters from Abraham Rattner, Henry Miller, and Anaïs Nin. Also includes typescript of "Odyssey of a Publisher" and holograph notes by Porter.
    - Porter, Bern. The Happy Rock. Layouts and illustration prints, 1945; 1 items. (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Porter, Bern. The Happy Rock. Two sets of galley proofs with printers' instructions, 1945; 2 items. (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - Porter, Bern. Henry Miller: a Chronology and Bibliography., undated; 4 items (4 typescripts of early versions with holograph corrections). (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - Porter, Bern. Henry Miller: a Chronology and Bibliography., undated; 1 item. Holograph and typescript notes. (Box 108, Folder 4)
      Includes correspondence with Lawrence Clark Powell.
    - Porter, Bern. Henry Miller: a Chronology and Bibliography., 1944-1945; ca. 29 items. (Box 108, Folder 5)
      Letters from various persons to Bern Porter. Includes several letters and notes from Henry Miller regarding the book, several drafts of the chronology, and a list of items missing from the draft of the bibliography.
    - Porter, Bern. Henry Miller: a Chronology and Bibliography., circa 1944; 5 items. Typescript, page proofs, layout, and book jackets (Box 108, Folder 6)
      Collected and published by Bern Porter, 1945.
    - Porter, Bern. Miscellaneous manuscripts regarding Henry Miller, undated; 6 items. (Box 108, Folder 7)
      Titles include: "A note on Henry Miller's works," "Letter to Gabene," "Mothering Tree," "The odyssey of a bankrupt publisher," and "Chez Henry Miller."
    - Porter, Bern. Miscellaneous notes, lists, and correspondence., circa 1944-1958; 1 item. (1st folder) 1 item. (2nd folder) (Box 109, Folder 1, Folder 2)
      Items by Bern Porter and others, collected by Porter. Includes notes by Miller to Bern Porter regarding his publications, note by Porter regarding the publication of the Red Notebook, notes by Porter on Miller biography, a list of addresses for persons.
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. "Henry Miller", 1980; 1 item. (Box 109, Folder 3)
      Xerox copy of Powell's tribute to Miller with reminiscences of their early friendship. Appeared in Westways magazine, August 1980.
    - Porter, Bern. "Original account book of Bern Porter - Henry Miller books", undated; 1 items. (Box 109, Folder 3)
    - Porter, Mrs. Valentine Mott. Notes on Henry Miller, 1945; 1 items. (Box 109, Folder 4)
      Notes written by Mrs. Porter on the reactions of several residents of Big Sur, California to Henry Miller. Note is in the form of a letter to "Dear Catherine." Gift of Wallace Fowlie, July 1975.
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. "Guest book, 2303 Loma vista Place. Los Angeles, 1934., 1941-1943; 1 item. (Box 109, Folder 5)
      Xeros copy of guest book kept by Lawrence and Fay Powell, beginning in 1934. The pages reproduced date from 1941 to 1943, with entries by Henry Miller.
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Letters to Henry Miller from The Famous and the Faceless, 1965; 11 items. (Box 109, Folder 6)
      Four typescript drafts. Originally titled: "Henry Miller: The Last of the Victorians." First published in the New York Times Book Review, May 9, 1965.
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Letters to Lawrence Clark Powell from various persons regarding Henry Miller, 1960-1971; 8 items. (Box 109, Folder 7)
      Includes letters from Eve Miller, Robert Snyder, and George Wickes.
    - Prosak, Frank. "Henry Miller's use of the alter ego in his autobiographical romances", 1969; 1 item. (Box 109, Folder 8)
      Thesis presented at University of Southern California.
    - Rexroth, Kenneth. "Miller comes at you like a caveman....", 1960; 1 item. (Box 109, Folder 9)
      Review of "The Henry Miller Reader."
    - Rosset, Barnet. "Henry Miller versus 'our way of life'", undated; 1 item. (Box 109, Folder 10)
      Photocopy, 7 leaves.
    - Sawyer, Paul W. "Dialouge between Epicurus, Henry Miller, and Carl Jung", undated; 1 item. (Box 109, Folder 11)
    - Schöffler, Heinz. "Henry Miller: ein literarisches porträt", undated; 1 item. (Box 109, Folder 12)
    - Schmiele, Walter. "Der Alte von Big Sur; neue Aspekte zum Bilde Henry Millers", 1958; 1 item. (Box 109, Folder 13)
      Mimeograph. Gift from Walter Schmiele to Henry Miller in 1958.
    - Schwarz, John M. "Henry Miller-Hilaire Hiler: two opposing views of art", 1966; 1 item. (Box 109, Folder 14)
      Mimeograph.
    - Sharon, Marvin. "Henry Miller: the quest to create a beginning", undated; 1 item. (Box 109, Folder 15)
    - Standish, Craig Peter. "I continue my ride on the ovarian trolley", 1979; 1 item. (Box 109, Folder 16)
      Scrapbook
    - Standish, Craig Peter. "I take a ride on the ovarian trolley", 1979; 1 item. (Box 109, Folder 17)
    - Standish, Craig Peter. "Thoughts on reading Love Between the Sexes", 1979; 1 item. (Box 109, Folder 18)
    - Thomas, Bob. "Adv sun ams", 1969; 1 item. (Box 110, Folder 1)
      Article on Miller by Associated Press writer, Bob Thomas.
    - Ueno, Ken-Ichi. [Two unidentified manuscripts in Japanese], undated; 2 items. (Box 110, Folder 2)
      2 typescripts one miscellaneous scraps of paper.
    - Wickes, George. Americans in Paris, circa 1967; 1 item. (Box 110, Folder 3)
    - Wickes, George. "An astral being", 1967; 1 item. (Box 110, Folder 4)
      Typescript (carbon) with holograph corrections. Review of "The Diary of Anaïs Nin, edited with an introduction by Gunther Struhlmann," New York, The Swallow Press and Harcourt, Brace & World, 1966.
    - Wickes, George. Review of Quite Days in Clichy, The World of Sex, Sexus, Plexus, and Nexus, entitled "The confessions of Henry Miller", 1965; 2 items. (Box 110, Folder 5)
      Typescript. Includes a letter from Wickes to Lawrence Clark Powell. Published in the New York Times Book Review, August 8, 1965, page 5, with the title, "Ecstasy is Lacking." Gift of Lawrence Clark Powell, July 1965.
    - Wickes, George. Henry Miller. Galleys, 1966; 1 item. (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - Wickes, George. Henry Miller., 1966; 1 item. Page proofs. (Box 110, Folder 7)